## Hello, I'm Luís Almeida



A frontend developer from Porto, Portugal, who loves to shape applications for the online world

🔗 luisalmeida.me 🔻 luiscvalmeida@gmail.com 🜎 github.com/luiscvalmeida 💆 twitter.com/luiscvalmeida

I've been working for the past 5 years as a frontend web developer using a wide range of technologies and languages, but mostly, javascript and everything around it.

During this time I've been lucky to work with awesome teams, learning new ways and techniques to develop and deliver applications for the web and it has been great!

Lately, I've been more focused on researching web performance optimization and fighting for those extra milliseconds faster page loads on server side rendered React applications.

## **Experience**

Mindera Porto, Portugal | 2016 - present

At Mindera I'm helping to build large applications with focus on scalability and continuous delivery. During this time I've been working mostly with React, Redux, and a lot of GraphQL (both consuming and building graph NodeJS servers), following a micro services architecture where everything is as automated as possible.

In here I've stepped a bit out of my comfort zone, setting up pipelines, deploying with Docker and Kubernetes - nowadays that's something I enjoy doing and look forward to do every time I get the chance. I've been working mainly for TVG, a Betfair company, helping to build their betting products.

At Mindera I've been playing with:

React, Redux, Angular, GraphQL, Apollo Client, Flow, Typescript, Styled Components, Express, NodeJS, Webpack, Jasmine, Jest, Karma, Lerna, Docker, Kubernetes, GoCD, Jenkins

**Ubiwhere** Aveiro, Portugal | 2014 - 2016

Responsible for developing small scale applications for the web using mostly AngularJS, mobile applications using Ionic framework and whole applications using Django, a python framework I've found to be really interesting. At Ubiwhere most of my work was around small/medium sized projects for the internet of things.

At Ubiwhere I played with: Django, AngularJS, LESS, SCSS, Grunt, Gulp, Jasmine, Karma

## **Education**

## Aveiro University Aveiro, Portugal | 2010-2015

I've completed a graduation in New Technologies Communication and later on, a master degree in Multimedia Communication. Both were around not only web development but also web design, which developed in me the sensibility to try to make things look as prettier as possible on every screen.